A key part of getting transitions to happen when we want
要使我们希望的状态转换过程发生
them to is the design of reasonable cost functions.
一项关键工作是设计出合理的成本函数
We want to penalize and reward the right things.
我们希望成本函数可以对事物做出正确评估
I'm going to work through an example of
我会通过一个例子
one way you might think about designing a cost function.
来启发大家思考有关设计成本函数的工作
Let's consider how we would design a cost function for vehicle speed.
大家考虑一下 我们如何为车辆速度设计成本函数
On one hand, we want to get to our destination quickly,
一方面 我们想尽快到达目的地
but on the other hand,
但是另一方面
we don't want to break the law.
我们又不想违反交规
An essential quantity we have to control is the desired velocity of the car.
我们需要的控制量 最基本的就是汽车的期望车速
Some velocities are more beneficial,
有些车速对驾驶非常有利
some are even illegal.
有些则会违反交规
Let's fill in this graph and try to assign some costs to every velocity.
现在我们来填一下这张图 试着为每个速度赋予一个成本
For the sake of simplicity,
基于简化考虑
let's assume that all of the cost functions will have an output between zero and one.
我们假定所有成本函数的输出值都位于0和1之间
We will adjust the importance of each cost function later by adjusting the weights.
后面我们会通过调整成本函数的权重 从而调节成本函数的相对重要性
Let's say the speed limit for the road we are on is here.
假设这是我们所在道路的限速值
Well, we know that if we're going well above the speed limit,
那么 我们都知道 如果速度超过限速值
that should be maximum cost.
那可能需要付出最大成本
And maybe we want to set
我们也许可以为
an ideal zero cost speed that's
一个理想速度设置成本值为0
slightly below the speed limit so that we have some buffer.
该速度应略低于限速 这样会有一些缓冲空间
And then we can think about how much we want to penalize not moving at all.
接下来 我们可以考虑一下 如果完全停止不动 成本会多大
Obviously, not moving is bad,
显然 完全不动肯定是不好的
but maybe not as bad as breaking the speed limit,
但是相对于超速 完全不动还是要好一点
so we would put it here.
所以我们把它设置为这里的值
To keep it simple,
简化起见
we could just say there is a linear cost between zero and the target speed.
我们假设成本值是线性的
And since breaking the law is a binary thing,
因为违反交规这种事情 只有是或否两种状态
let's just say any speed greater than or equal the speed limit has maximal cost.
所以我们设定 任何大于或等于限速值的速度都拥有最大的成本
And again, we can arbitrarily connect these points with
接下来 我们可以任意地将这些点数和一个线性函数相关联
a linear function and the flat maximum cost for anything above the speed limit.
并把任何大于限速的速度和恒定最大成本相关联
Now, in practice, we might actually want to parametrize some of
现在 我们或许想要真正参数化这些量中的一部分
these quantities so that we could later adjust them until we got the right behavior.
然后我们就可以通过调整参数 从而获得不错的行为
So first, we might define a parameter called Stop Cost for
那么现在 我们可以为车辆的完全停止状态
the zero-velocity case and a parameter called
定义一个称为 Stop Cost 的参数
buffer velocity which would probably be a few miles per hour.
我们还可以定义一个叫 buffer velocity 的参数 值大概是每小时几公里
Then, our overall cost function has three domains.
然后 我们的成本函数有三个域
If we're going less than the target speed,
如果我们行驶速度小于目标速度
the cost function would look like this.
成本函数看起来将会是这样的
If we are above the speed limit,
如果我们超过限速
the cost is just one.
成本就变成了1
And if we are between,
如果我们处于目标速度和限速之间
the cost would look like this. Awesome.
成本看起来是这样的 这个结果相当不错